# **Aaron James Banda**

Mobile: E-mail: Website: (+63) 918 669-10-76 ajibanda@gmail.com https://ajibanda.github.io/ http://www.ajibanda.com

#### **PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY**

A developer with extensive experience in developing and supporting mission critical applications. A purposedriven professional active in engaging, training and mentoring others. Bringing an in-depth understanding of software deployment and system design illustrated over years of experience in similar roles.

## **SKILLS**

**Programming Language** C/C++, Assembly

Scripting Language Ruby, PHP, JavaScript (JQuery), AJAX

**Database** MySQL, SQLite

**Frameworks** Rails, Laravel, Codelgniter, Twitter Bootstrap

**Server Management** UNIX Operating Systems (Ubuntu, CentOS), Cloud, Virtual Private Servers,

Remote Shell Access (SSH), FTP/DNS, WHM, Virtual Box

Others WordPress, Joomla! (CMS), Flash Builder / Flex,

Adobe AIR Applications (AJAX/HTML), PhoneGap, Search Engine Optimization (SEO), HTML, CSS

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### **SOFTWARE DESIGN ENGINEER**

**SparkSoft Solutions, Inc.** (*Previously Blue Chip Designs, Inc.*) 2008-2019

**Job Description:** Responsible for planning, designing and full-stack development of projects up to its deployment stage. Also assists lower-level programmers and work closely with clients.

## **Optical Shop Inventory System (2019)**

Designed a system to monitor sales and inventory of a shop with multiple branches.

## Front-desk Visitor Login System

Digitized visitors' login system that generates statistics report regarding the visitor flow.

# Back-end monitoring for an Internet Provider Client (2017-2018)

Maintains a system designed to monitor multiple servers and other related systems.

# **Roving Guard Monitoring (2017-2018)**

Created a GPS-based system used to track security guards monitoring an area.

# **Machine Efficiency Monitoring System (2016-2017)**

Devised a system for a manufacturing company that to check and monito the efficiency of their equipment by tracking the time of usage and production's output.

## Pharmaceutical ERP (2015-2019)

Designed an online system used to track sales from purchasing procedures to delivery to clients. Includes basic accounting procedure to trace clients' payments and printing of invoices and delivery receipts.

## SparkSIS (2014-2019)

The predecessor of A-B-SIS; Re-structured the system as it was revised and repackaged to cope with the current K-12 educational system.

## Online DBMS for Member Tracking (2013-2019)

Designed a system structure for a multinational company DBMS that is used for tracking and managing its members under their program which includes training schedules and profiling.

# SurveyPlus (2013-2014)

Devised a mobile data-collecting system that is generally used for marketing research and surveys via Android devices. This includes a web server for storing and analyzing of data collected.

## iSecure-PhilJust (Online Bar Review) (2012-2013)

Created a pay-per view bar review web application for lawyers and students.

# i-CALL (Online Language Tutorial) (2011-2012)

Developed an online English tutorial site that handles matching of teachers and students and plotting it in a calendar for scheduling.

## Baul (Ballads and Epics Archive) (2010) http://epics.ateneo.edu/epics

Put up an archive site for a Philippine anthropologist's collection. The archive itself stores videos, audio files, photos and articles about the different ballads, epics and traditions of 15 local linguistic groups.

It was redesigned to a PHP based framework (fro ROR) in 2014 due to a client's request.

# iGolping (SwingPractis application) (2010) http://vimeo.com/28180393/

Handled the front-end of a *Flex* application for a golf simulation.

# VideoVitae (Job Searching Website) (2009)

Worked on a Joomla! based website for online job searching that stores videos as means of application.

# A-B-SIS (School Information System) (2008)

Developed an online school information system that allows the schools and universities to manage procedures and other functions even for multiple branches.

## **EDUCATION**

## **Bachelor of Science Degree in Computer Engineering**

Pamantasan ng Lungsod ng Maynila (*University of the City of Manila*) Intramuros, Manila; S.Y. 2003–2008

Dean's Lister (2004-2008)

DOST-SEI (R.A. 7687) Scholar (2003-2008)

Department of Science and Technology through Science Education Institute